<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 
 <title>BLOG_NAME</title>
 <link href="YOUR_URL/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="YOUR_URL"/>
 <updated>2016-02-06T16:15:04+05:30</updated>
 <id>BLOG_URL</id>
 <author>
   <name>BLOG_NAME</name>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>Skill Development Landscape In India</title>
   <link href="YOUR_URL/2016/01/07/skill-development-landscape-in-india/"/>
   <updated>2016-01-07T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
   <id>BLOG_URL/2016/01/07/skill-development-landscape-in-india</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Skills and knowledge are the driving forces of economic growth and social development for any country. Countries with higher and better levels of skills adjust more effectively to the challenges and opportunities of world of work. As India moves progressively towards becoming a ‘knowledge economy’ it becomes increasingly important that the country should focus on advancement of skills and these skills have to be relevant to the emerging economic environment. In order to achieve the twin targets of economic growth and inclusive development, India’s Gross Domestic Product (GDP) has to grow consistently at 8% to 9% per annum. This requires significant progress in several areas, including infrastructure development, agricultural growth coupled with productivity improvements, financial sector growth, a healthy business environment, ably supported by a skilled workforce.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Talent Situation in the Indian IT-BPM Industry:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Graduate talent supply for the IT-BPM Industry is not just restricted to Engineers or technically qualified talent. In fact with the scope of services being offered by BPM - Finance, Medical, Legal and almost every professional is part of the potential talent pool. Out of the 5-5.5 million graduates that pass out every year, only about 0.6-0.7 million are considered employable by Tier 1/Tier 2 companies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Talent supply for the BPM Sector (Only Non-Technical Graduates):&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The BPM sector consists of areas such as F&amp;amp;A, HR Outsourcing, Legal Process, Medical processes, etc. apart from the much-famed Customer Support processes. The scenario below assumes that only non-technical graduates, such as graduates from Commerce, Arts, Science, etc. backgrounds are willing to join the BPM sub-sector. The current total potential supply (those who are willing to work) to this sub-sector is around 2.5 million. However only about 0.45-0.5 million are considered employable by the industry. With the implementation of NOS, we expect an approximate increase of more than 200 per cent in the number of employable candidates to about 1.3-1.5 million. This has been estimated as a result on improvement on filtering out ratios for factors; General and Technical Aptitude (from ~60 per cent to ~90 per cent) and Soft Skills (from ~33 per cent to ~70 per cent).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Projected Demand and Demand-Supply Gap in ITes Industry:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Projected Demand:&lt;/strong&gt; On a long-term basis, up to 2022, it is expected that India’s GDP will grow at a CAGR of about 8%. With these growth rates, we expect that the employment in the economy will be about 500 million by 2022. For an economy to sustain this growth rate it is essential that the workforce be exposed to some form of skilling or the other (could be through higher/technical education or vocation skills or a combination of both). Thus it is expected that India will have to be home to a skilled workforce of 500 million persons by 2022.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Projected Supply:&lt;/strong&gt; Among all the countries, India enjoys a unique advantage not only to fulfil its internal demand of skilled manpower, but also cater to the labour shortage in other countries. The government is taking proactive steps to fill the existing skill gap to leverage its position as a supplier of skilled manpower to the world. India is expected to grow at a rate of 8 percent on an average in the next 10 years. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More than 700 million Indians are estimated to be of working age by 2022. Out of these, more than 500 million require some kind of vocational or skill development training. In the Twelfth Five Year Plan, the country has set a tough challenge in the field of vocational education and training to tackle this skill gap in the future. It aims to increase the percentage of workforce with formal skills to 25 per cent at the end of the plan. It is estimated that 50–70 million jobs will be created in India over the next five years and about 75 percent –90 percent of these additional employment avenues will require some vocational training.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Analysis of Talent Demand and Supply&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The supply side issues of quality and quantity signals a concerning picture. Only 0.15 million technically qualified candidates are estimated to be employable in the non-BPM sub-sectors out of the ~0.78 million people supplied from technical streams in 2013. This proportion is lower for other streams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:3000/images/image001.png&quot; alt=&quot;talent demand and supply&quot; title=&quot;talent demand and supply&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If no actions are taken to improve the employability situation, there could be an extreme excess of graduates leading to large-scale unemployment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:3000/images/image003.png&quot; alt=&quot;talent demand and supply&quot; title=&quot;talent demand and supply&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Assuming an average growth rate of~9 percent per annum, the talent pool available is expected to stay in excess of the talent demand for the coming few years. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Challenges faced by the IT / ITeS Sector in India&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;• Increasing input costs in Tier 1 cities are pushing companies to Tier 2 and 3 cities : The Indian IT &amp;amp; ITeS sector primarily operates through six major states, including Karnataka, Andhra Pradesh, Maharashtra, Tamil Nadu, Haryana and Uttar Pradesh — major centers of top IT &amp;amp; ITeS firms such as TCS, Infosys, HCL, Tech Mahindra, Cognizant and Capgemini are based in these states. Also, a majority of these centers are based in tier 1 cities of these states, such as Bengaluru, Chennai, Hyderabad, Gurgaon and Noida. As infrastructure facilities in tier 1 cities saturate and input costs increase, IT &amp;amp; ITeS companies are shifting their focus towards tier 2 and 3 cities. Some of these cities include Ahmedabad, Jaipur, Nagpur, Bhubaneshwar, Mangalore, Guwahati and Chandigarh&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;• IT / ITeS sector is expected to provide employment to over 5 million people by 2022.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;• Intake of students for PG  Courses forms a miniscule % of total intakes in engineering and technology institutes. - CAGR of intake over the period 2006 - 2014 for UG courses, PG courses and Diploma courses is 13.84%, 15.52%, and 9.45% respectively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;• Less than 10% of institutes constitutes the top quality pyramid  in engineering education offering cutting edge Education&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:3000/images/image005.png&quot; alt=&quot;quality pyramid  in engineering education&quot; title=&quot;quality pyramid  in engineering education&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Skill Development Landscape in Haryana&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Haryana is the largest commercial center in northern India. The highest per capita income in the country attracts sizable investment from multinational companies, foreign investors, large business houses and small scale industries. It is the preferred destination for investors globally as the state is bordering the National Capital from three sides. Haryana’s close contact with Delhi provides numerous investment opportunities in various sectors of the State economy. Haryana boasts many excellent locations to their investors for setting up their industrial units. In addition to that, around 40% of the NCR falls in Haryana State and 30% of the State is notified NCR. 
Information Technology (IT) has been recognized as one of the priority sectors in the economy. Accordingly, the State Government has formulated an IT policy which provides several incentives for IT and ITES/BPO Industry. It has also recently announced a policy for Technology Parks, which gives considerable flexibility for setting up Technology Parks and IT Corridors. All such efforts aim to promote convergence of Information Technology with frontier technologies like Nano Technology, Bio Technology, Mobile Computing and Robotics, etc. Further, Gurgaon has been developed as a preferred investment destination for both IT and ITES/BPO companies. Over the years, it has become the home of the corporate world in India. The State Government is planning to set up Hi-Tech Habitat Centre in the Electronic City, Gurgaon for IT/ITES/BPO companies, which would provide world-class facilities. Besides Gurgaon, the Government also intends to develop other areas in NCR region, such as those falling alongside Kundli-Manesar-Palwal Express Highway and Faridabad, as satellites of Gurgaon-Manesar Mega IT Hub. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Projected Demand and Supply of Manpower:&lt;/strong&gt;
In line with the trend as observed in most parts of Northern India, it is expected that Haryana will experience a huge bulge in its working age population between the years 2012-22. This makes the task of skilling even more important and challenging in order to reap benefits of the state’s demographic dividend. It is estimated that between 2012 and 2017, Haryana will add 1.73 million people to its working age population and a further 1.51 million during the period 2017-2022.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:3000/images/image007.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:3000/images/image009.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Growth of IT/ITes Sector in Haryana&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The state government, over the past decade, has undertaken several initiatives towards transforming Haryana into an IT driven economy. The state had drafted the IT Policy way back in 2000. With increasing focus on adoption of IT in every sphere of public service activity, the sector is expected to continue contributing significantly to the economy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The state government is pro actively involved in furthering Haryana standing in the IT services sector. The IT policy52 of the state encourages setting up Technology Parks, Cyber Cities, IT Corridors and other IT related industries in the state. The state also seeks to converge other cutting edge technologies like Bio Technology, Robotics and Nano Technology with Information Technology. Gurgaon has emerged as the IT hub for the state, nearly all major IT companies in India are present in Gurgaon. The IT/ITES exports reached INR 23,000 crores53 in 2009-10. The Haryana Government has granted 33 licenses for Cyber/IT parks, 35 IT/ITES SEZs and 10 technology parks coming up at the Industrial Model Township Manesar&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:3000/images/image011.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gross Enrollment Capacity of Haryana 18.9 seats per 1000 population is higher than national average of 13.7 seats per 1000 population. This is however lower than the average Gross Enrollment Ratio of developed countries which is often above 50%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The international best practice followed in the education system, is to allow seamless transition of students at various stages (from secondary school onwards) into vocational education streams. In order to facilitate this, vocational education curriculum is incorporated in education at the schooling stage itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:3000/images/image013.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;h3&gt;Challenges in IT/ITeS Sector in Haryana&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lack of soft skills amongst local youth&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the key issues faced by the industries in the state was poor soft skills, lack of professional behavior and low work ethics amongst local youths. This has resulted in certain industries hiring as high as 80 percent 
of entry level workforce from other states&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, this has resulted in only worsening of the situation as local youth feel marginalized, and hence lower flexibility amongst them&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;High influx of migratory labour&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Haryana has traditionally witnessed high labour population from Uttar Pradesh and Bihar primarily on account of better opportunities. While, traditionally this migration was for agriculture related activities, these 
workers are also now joining industries and are seen to contribute to significant share of entry level workforce&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lack of uniform training and evaluation standards&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lack of uniform training and evaluation standards leads to various issues ranging from limited acceptability of certain training certifications in industry, to misalignment of training with industry needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently, NCVT &amp;amp; GCVT courses are being offered in ITI s/ ITCs, while private training institutions/ industry led training bodies offer individual certifications. There is a need to bring in uniform standards across institutes in order to achieve uniform quality of training 
and certification&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Continuing Demand - Supply Gap leading to after school dropouts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While higher education capacities have registered significant growth, considering the low base, the gap continues. Capacity gaps along with affordability, are key reasons for drop outs either during schooling 
years, or just after schooling especially in economically backward districts&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the GER targets for India (30% by the end of 12th plan period 2012
-17) have to be matched, the current higher education capacity in Haryana has to be increased by one third by 2017&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Poor Branding of  Vocational Education&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The social perception about Vocational Education was poor across the state. Most parents and students were seen to opt for Vocational Education for primarily either of two reasons – less economic burden as well or inability to garner admission in any other higher education course &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ineffective teacher training&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Majority of the Govt ITI faculty met during the primary survey did not receive any relevant training programs during their service. Even for the faculty which did undergo the programs did not find it adequate. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Adhoc training programs and lack of formal refresher courses have in turn resulted in poor training quality 
Lower percentage of skilled persons in the workforce
The skill level and educational attainment of the work force determines the productivity as well as the adaptability of the working class in changing environment. Majority of workforce both present &amp;amp; potential do not possess requisite skills and need to undergo training. Only 5% of the Indian labour force in the age group of 20-24 has received vocational training whereas the percentage in industrialized countries is much higher, varying between 60% and 80%&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Preference for Employment Vs Entrepreneurship:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The youth interviewed exhibited a high preference towards employment over entrepreneurship in almost all districts, except Faridabad. A number of ITI students have set up their own small scale units in Faridabad. Several factors such as poor financial capacity, work environment and socio-cultural factors influenced youth preferences towards employment. Entry level salaries in industries and awareness of career opportunities in the district are other pivotal factors influencing 
youth preference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Choice of Education and Training Stream:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Economic background of an individual is one of the key factors influencing the program chosen for study. Along with economic background awareness level about the programs typically acquired through family members/seniors is another major influencing parameter.
In terms of choice of education, there is a poor perception of vocational training and it remains as one of least preferred option. Students from weaker sections of the society, both economically and socially, are seen to opt for vocational courses over higher education programs primarily due to financial constraints.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Awareness of career opportunities:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Awareness of career opportunities was limited or medium across most 
districts. Low levels of awareness of career opportunities. Higher awareness levels were observed only districts like Faridabad and Gurgaon. While jobs fairs and motivational camps were held at the 
many institutes to help students understand the various career opportunities available to them, the effectiveness of those were limited. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;*&lt;em&gt;Government of Haryana has attempted many measures to promote skill development in the state. While the objectives of skill development initiatives are sound, implementation of the initiatives is fraught with 
challenges. *&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The government has been in the forefront of implementing several Central and State funded skill training initiatives like the pilot project launched in 2012 under the National Vocational Education Qualification. However there is a need to create a mechanism to ensure the effectiveness of skill development programs. This would improve the achievement of learning outcomes and employability in the open market of students&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;*&lt;em&gt;Outdated curriculum *&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the curriculum has not been revised since the 1960s, when it was conceived, industries have found it hard to employ candidates from district ITIs as there is a mismatch in expectations. Currently, there is no
formal mechanism to periodically review and revise the curriculum based on industry requirements. Traditional engineering trades, though popular amongst students, are decreasing in their relevance to industry, due to 
increase automation and technology deployment - e.g.: Welding, Turner, Fitting etc. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lack of infrastructure for IT Education Institutes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With regard to faculty and management of institutions, there needs to be an upgradation of facilities and infrastructure support. While funding may not be an issue for most government ITIS, maintenance of equipments is viewed as a liability by faculty. This in turn affects training schedule. Contract faculties have a lack of motivation (stemming from low salaries) even though they comprise as high as 80 percent of faculty in districts like Jhajjar. There is also a faculty shortage in districts like Gurgaon, a problem further compounded by very long recruitment cycles, recruitment turnaround time can range anywhere from 6 months to a year. The training offered to teachers is not effective and even the frequency at which it is imparted is very low &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disillusionment with the objective of the apprenticeship programs.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In terms of student training, there seems to be a general disillusionment with the objective of the apprenticeship programs. Apprentices are not seen as serious candidates for employment and rarely do these programs lead to placements. Most students receive very low stipends of about INR 2000 per month which is not sufficient to sustain student interest and motivation. Lack of industry support further demotivates students who are a part of these courses. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;No Clear mandate on hiring by Corporates.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In terms of placements, ITIs in Haryana must be more proactive in ensuring employment opportunities for students. There is a problem of branding with ITIs,where the perception is very poor. Placements for 
those students in short term courses are not guaranteed, as these students are not taken seriously by employers. The situation is further worsened by the fact that students are not willing to migrate outside the district at low entry level wages of INR 4,000 to INR 5,000 per month. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lack of skilled manpower and basic trade related knowledge.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quality of skilled manpower in the district is not up to par with industry expectations. Industry has alleged that in some districts candidates lack even the basic trade related knowledge and machine handling skills. Lack of multi skilling is another complaint; ITIs should offer more options to students. Lack of industry relevant courses further disadvantage candidates. All of this results in significant spending on in house training by the industries themselves to prepare candidates in both technical and non technical areas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Recommendations&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Recommendations and Implications&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h5&gt;Better industry academia Partnerships&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Industry should collaborate with colleges to set up research labs in the college campuses.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Summer internships should be made an integral part of the curriculum.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Colleges should reach out to more and more industry experts to have them as guest faculties&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Industry needs to encourage continuing education programs for their employees in collaboration with leading universities and colleges&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h5&gt;Capacity building in regions with low density of training infrastructure&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Government should set up technical institutes in regions with low density of engineering colleges&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;State governments with low density of engineering colleges should provide incentives to private players to set up technical institutes in their states&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h5&gt;Focus on improving the quality of faculty and also on increasing the faculty strength&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Increased focus on up-scaling programs would help improve faculty quality&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Colleges and universities should focus on improving the research infrastructure. Well funded Ph.D programs with opportunities for international exposure should be rolled out to attract students who currently look to pursue Ph.D outside the country&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;More institutes which provide trainer certification programs should be set up via PPP model&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h5&gt;Focus on soft skill training&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Colleges and training institutes should focus on developing good communication skills amongst the students pursuing education in IT and ITeS related fields.
Encourage institutes to offer cross-sectoral degrees&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Institutes should offer IT modules across other streams of engineering &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IT modules should be embedded in the curriculum of other specializations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h5&gt;Rationalization of targets allotted to current partners&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make provision for additional capacity because existing partners might not be able to meet the targets allotted to them &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create additional capacities in select identified courses/geographies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h5&gt;Reforming the regulatory framework&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An independent regulatory authority should be set up by the government.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This agency would be responsible for setting the criteria for entry, granting permissions for entry to higher education institutes, according degree granting power, monitoring standards and settling disputes, licensing accreditation agencies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Government should increase the financing for higher education&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Government should float education bonds and elite institutes must be encouraged to raise funds by themselves&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h5&gt;Making certification by SSC more acceptable&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Map up-scaling training to SSC certification&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There should be a mandate given to the industry to hire only trained or certified manpower&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Status Of Haryana Power - Background, Challenges & Waysahead</title>
   <link href="YOUR_URL/2016/01/06/status-of-haryana-power/"/>
   <updated>2016-01-06T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
   <id>BLOG_URL/2016/01/06/status-of-haryana-power</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h4&gt;A. BACKGROUND&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;An efficient, resilient and financially robust power sector is essential for industrial expansion, economic growth and thereby poverty reduction. It is a critical input for manufacturing, services, agriculture and other allied activities.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The power sector in Haryana was unbundled into four State owned Public Sector companies after the enactment of Electricity Act, 2003. So, now power sector in Haryana comprises of four companies, namely Haryana Power Generation Corporation Ltd. (HPGCL), Haryana Vidyut Prasaran Nigam Ltd. (HVPNL), Uttar Haryana Bijli Vitran Nigam Ltd. (UHBVN), Dakshin Haryana Bijli Vitran Nigam Ltd. (DHBVN). As per the mandate of the act, the tariff charged by these companies is determined by an independent regulator i.e. the Haryana Electricity Regulatory Commission (HERC).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Although, Power sector is a regulated sector but the generation division had got delicensed and since then captive generation has been freely permitted. The interstate power trading is governed by Central Electricity Regulatory Commission (CERC) and intra state power trading is regulated by HERC.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;In terms of power availability, Haryana is a power surplus state. It has a power generation capacity (including long term sourcing arrangement from Adani power) of around 10,000 MW per annum, whereas demand for power in the state is around 4000 MW for non peak hours and around 6000 MW in peak hours, thus creating a position of power surplus.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;While all the three sectors of power-generation, transmission and distribution are important, but revenues for the power sector originate with the consumer at the distribution, so subpar performance in distribution division thereby hurt the entire value chain. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Presently, the state has monopoly over the distribution sector. After achieving the Annual Gross Revenue of Rs 21500 crore the two companies in the distribution  suffer annual loss of around 3500 crore i.e.  NP to sales ratio is negative (around 16%).The average cost of purchase of power is around Rs3.90 per unit while average realisation per unit is around Rs.7.35. This indicates that the cost of serving the transaction is abnormally high.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;With the central government proposing to bring an amendment in the electricity act of 2003 to provide retail competition and to allow power traders to participate in the distribution areas, a serious question arises that, are our state owned distribution companies ready to face the challenges?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;B. CHALLENGES&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Even after being a power surplus state, the state cannot provide 24*7 electricity to its consumers. This is primarily due to the leakages and inefficiencies built in the distribution sector over the last so many years. The State is practically running sick companies to serve its people. The net worth of these distribution companies had already eroded long back. These companies carry a debt burden of around thirty thousand crores mainly to cover its losses.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Generation companies are also not in a position to sell electricity in the open market because of its high cost of production as compared to the Open market Rate. For e.g. Adani Power sells power at Rs. 3.30 per unit (ex destination) Mahindergarh whereas Haryana produces power costing between Rs. 4 to 5.50 per unit (ex factory) and average transmission cost ranges around 50 paise depending upon the destination.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The distribution sector is plagued with huge level of theft prevalent mostly in the rural households and unauthorised colonies (Aggregate Technical &amp;amp; Commercial Loss ranges between 26% to 36%). This along with the subsidy bill (to the farmer through the provisions of Budget) of around 6000 crore  is hitting the state hard. It is causing a direct and indirect loss to the state amounting to Rs. 9428 crores (planning commission) whereas the total budgetary resources available to state (including both tax and non tax revenues) are around 40,000 crores i.e. 24% of the total resources of the state is being spent on covering the loss. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Comparing these figures with the budgetary allocation to other sectors, the situation looks even worse. The budget allocated to health is only around Rs. 3000 crores, 2800 crore Rs is allocated to Urban Development and State Police has a budget of around Rs3000 crore. Clearly, with such huge losses and cost in the distribution sector, the state is not in a position to allocate funds to other important sectors.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;C. WAYSAHEAD&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Management, Operations and Finances of the distribution companies must be improved on an immediate basis. This will not only improve the condition of the state finances but also the image of the government among the public at large in providing public services efficiently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In our view, the losses of the distribution sector can be addressed in the following ways:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;There can be two ways to handle these huge losses, one is to increase the revenue and the other is to cut the costs. Revenues can be increased by using innovative ways to generate non tariff Income. For instance, polls owned by these companies can be rented away to install/put up digital cables/optical fibres. So, this will generate rent income for distribution companies. We can add some Innovative services and can charge service fee. Some lessons can be learnt from our banks which have recently adopted service based fee apart from the controlled segment of Interest leverage. Likewise, the distribution companies can set up Tatkaal Connection or 24 hour van service and dedicated call centres to address the grievance against some user charges. This will give additional income and will also increase customer satisfaction level. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The second way is to increase the revenues in a phased manner. In the urban areas, temporary connection can be given to the unauthorised colonies. Whereas for rural areas where power theft is rampant Franchise Model of bill recovery can be set up by incentivising local people to collect the bills and end theft.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The other way to handle the huge losses is to contain the costs. This can be done by optimising the power Purchase at minimum possible cost. There should also be a proper audit of the expenses of these companies.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The third way is to increase the volume where revenue realisation is full by creating separate Customer Relationship manager. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;So, the state power utility companies have to realise first that they are service providers to the society and that they are running a Commercial Enterprise. Hence, they are answerable to all the stakeholders including Owners, Customers, Employees, Lenders, Regulators and society at large. The entire Board has to take a professional approach and should engage with the large consulting houses in the area of management, information technology (IT) and commercial law. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Surprisingly, there are no robust HR practices in state power utilities, whereas HR is the utmost important asset for any Service Providing company. Well Defined Selection process, Regular Training system to upgrade the skills set, attitude level, Performance evaluation Process, Remuneration and incentive mechanism is imperative to attract and retain the talent in the system so as to create a successful company.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;If the companies in the distribution division of the power sector get crippled by the competition caused by private companies, the state might have to bear the burden of debt of about 30,000 crores. In order to prevent such a situation and solve the above mentioned problems of the power sector an immediate interference by professionals is required. It is also high time now that accounting reforms be introduced in these companies to align their accounting practices with any other private company. Also, an active and professional board, the introduction of IT techniques, best management practices more particularly HR, bringing in experts in power sector is immediately needed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 
</feed>